safedrivingforlife.info 2016-05-10

# Privacy and Cookies | DVSA - Safe Driving for Life

## Introduction

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to set out the manner and purposes for which we will obtain and process your personal information. By using this website, you are consenting to the collection and use of your personal information in the way we describe in this Policy and to our Terms and Conditions.

## Who We Are

This website is hosted and managed by TSO (The Stationery Office Limited). Registered address: 29 St John's Lane, London, EC1M 4NA. TSO is a registered Data Controller as defined by the UK Data Protection Act 1998 (Act). We obtain, process and store personal information in accordance with the Act and all other applicable UK privacy legislation.

## Obtaining Your Personal Information

We may obtain personal information about you when you register to use this website, place an order with us or when you provide feedback about our products or services.

## Processing Your Personal Information

We will use the personal information that you provide us with to process your order for our products or services and to ensure that any goods ordered are delivered to the address specified.

When you place an order with us we may, if necessary, contact you to confirm that we are fulfilling the order in accordance with your instructions and according to our own high standards. We may also contact you to provide or obtain any other pertinent information concerning your order.

When you enquire or provide feedback about our products and services we will use the contact details that you have provided to respond to you.

Any feedback that you provide will help us to understand how our products and services are perceived by our customers and which of our products and services are of most interest. We may use such information to tailor our service offerings to suit your needs and improve our product and service offerings for the benefit of our customers generally.

In order to source the product that you require and ensure that it is delivered to the delivery address that you have specified as quickly as possible, it sometimes may be necessary for us to pass your delivery address details to an external publisher or supplier acting on our behalf to enable them to dispatch the goods that you have ordered directly to you. However, your order will always be managed by TSO and we will only provide our suppliers with the minimum information necessary to facilitate the delivery of the goods to you, such as your name, address and the details of the products to be supplied. Our suppliers have provided sufficient security guarantees in relation to any personal information that we might provide them with for these purposes and they are required to act only on our instructions in relation to any such information.

## Direct Marketing Material

We will use your personal information to keep you informed of products, services and events that we feel may be of interest to you or your business. We may also use your personal information to keep you informed of new and/or existing products that are similar to those which you have previously purchased.

You may at any time ask us to cease or not commence sending you direct marketing material by contacting our customer services division on Tel: +44 (0)333 202 5070 or by sending an email to [tsoproductupdates@tso.co.uk](mailto:tsoproductupdates@tso.co.uk).

Upon receipt of notification that you do not wish to receive marketing material from us, we will action your request within a reasonable time period.

## Email Marketing Communications

TSO offers a free email newsletter subscription service to keep you informed of our products and services. All recipients of our newsletter have either consented to receiving such material or have placed an order with us for similar products or services.

We incorporate a tracking system in our email marketing communications which allows us to monitor whether the email has been opened and which links are the most popular. This allows us to tailor and refine our service to ensure that the emails you receive are relevant to your interests.

Where you have consented to receiving email marketing material from us or are currently receiving material relating to similar products or services, you may at any time ask us to cease sending you such material by sending an email to [tsoproductupdates@tso.co.uk](mailto:tsoproductupdates@tso.co.uk) with the heading unsubscribe or you can go to your [**free updates page**](http://10.254.170.61/webshop/bookstore.asp?ACTION=PRODUCTUPDATES&TRACKID=000578) (you will need to login if you have not already done so) and click the 'unsubscribe' link at the foot of the page. Unsubscribe instructions are also clearly outlined at the bottom of every direct marketing email that we send you.

## Cookies

### What are cookies?

Cookies are tiny text files stored on your browser. We use cookies to remember your visits to our website to improve your user experience. EU legislation states that all websites should let you know when they are using cookies. Most websites use cookies and they won't cause any harm to your device. This website uses cookies to help us see which pages our customers like and which aren't working so well, so we can make improvements. Cookies don't tell us who you are or give us any personal details about you.

If you do not accept the cookies you will still be able to browse our site but some parts of the site will not work.

### Which cookies do we use on this site and why?

The table below sets out the main cookies that we use on this site and what we use them for.

Type of Cookie | Cookie name | Expires after | Purpose  
---|---|---|---  
Site performance | Web Trends | 10 years | Performance cookies collect anonymous information about how visitors use our website, for example how many visitors came to our website and when, what browsers visitors use and how long visitors stay on the site. This data does not contain any information that is personal to you.  
Google Analytics: __utma | 2 years from set/update  
Google Analytics: __utmb | 30 minutes from set/update  
Google Analytics: __utmc | not set  
Google Analytics: __utmz | 6 months from set/update  
SiteStat: c1 | 5 years  
SiteStat: s1  
BIG-IP | same day  
Session | has_js | browser is closed | 

These cookies are necessary to enable the website to perform essential functionality such as browsing web pages.  
  
Drupal session | 23 days  
  
### Enabling and disabling cookies

This website uses cookies to remember your site preferences. If you decline cookies you may lose some of the beneficial website functions of cookies. No personally identifiable information is stored within cookies. Therefore, we recommend you leave these turned on. To check if cookies are enabled on your device, please follow the steps below. Alternatively, view your browser's help pages or information on how to manage cookies at [www.allaboutcookies.org .](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

### Internet Explorer

  1. Click on Tools > Internet Options in the main toolbar
  2. Select Privacy tab to view your settings
  3. Move the slider to the level of privacy you prefer - privacy levels are shown in the table below.

Select this | To specify this  
---|---  
  
Block All Cookies

| 

Cookies from all websites will be blocked.  
  
Cookies that are already on your computer cannot be read by websites.  
  
High

| 

Cookies from all websites that do not have a compact policy (a condensed, computer-readable privacy statement) will be blocked.  
  
Cookies from all websites that use information that can be used to contact you without your explicit consent will be blocked.  
  
Medium High

| 

Cookies from third-party websites that do not have a compact policy (a condensed, computer-readable privacy statement) will be blocked.  
  
Cookies from third-party websites that use information that can be used to contact you without your explicit consent will be blocked.  
  
Cookies from first-party websites that use information that can be used to contact you without your implicit consent will be deleted from your computer when you close Internet Explorer.  
  
Medium

| 

Cookies from third-party websites that do not have a compact policy (a condensed, computer-readable privacy statement) will be blocked.  
  
Cookies from third-party websites that use information that can be used to contact you without your implicit consent will be blocked.  
  
Cookies from first-party websites that use information that can be used to contact you without your implicit consent will be deleted from your computer when you close Internet Explorer.  
  
Low

| 

Cookies from third-party websites that do not have a compact policy (a condensed, computer-readable privacy statement) will be blocked.  
  
Cookies from third-party websites that use information that can be used to contact you without your implicit consent will be deleted from your computer when you close Internet Explorer.  
  
Accept All Cookies

| 

All websites will be allowed to save cookies on your computer.  
  
Cookies that are already on your computer can be read by the websites that created them.  
  
### Google Chrome

  1. Click the spanner icon in the top right hand corner of the browser and select Settings from the drop-down menu
  2. Click on Show advanced settings at the bottom of the page
  3. Select Content Settings under the Privacy heading
  4. Manage your preferred cookies settings from this page.

### Safari (Mac only)

  1. Click on Safari in the toolbar, then select Preferences from the drop-down menu
  2. Click Privacy to view Cookie preferences (Note: Safari blocks third-party cookies by default).

### Further information

For further information regarding cookies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

## Data Protection & Information Security

Our e-commerce activities are certified to the best practice information security standard ISO 27001 and we follow strict security procedures for obtaining, processing and storing the personal information with which we have been entrusted.

We will not disclose or make your personal information available to a third party (otherwise than where indicated within this Privacy Policy) without your consent.

You can help to protect your personal information by ensuring that you keep your login password secure. We also recommend that you log out of your account once you have completed your transaction or enquiry, especially if you are using a shared computer.

We will at your request, provide you with a copy of any personal information that we are holding about you. We will charge an administration fee of £10 on each occasion that such a request is made and we will require you to prove that you are the person who is the subject of the information that we are holding before disclosing it to you.

We will also correct or delete any inaccurate information that we are holding about you that is brought to our attention.

To request a copy of any personal information that we are holding about you please email [foirequest@tso.co.uk](mailto:foirequest@tso.co.uk).

## Links to Other Websites

This website may contain links to other third party websites with whom we have a relationship. However, we are not responsible for these websites and their privacy practices. We therefore suggest that you read the privacy policy statements on any website that you visit from a link on this site, as their policies and procedures may differ from our own.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

If we decide to change this Privacy Policy we will post the changes here. However, if we intend to make material changes to the way we use your personal information we will seek your consent before doing so.

## Contacting Us

Our aim is to ensure that we offer you the very best personal service; the kind of service you want and the products you need. Your views are important to us; it would therefore greatly assist us if you could let us know of any way that we can improve our service to you by contacting us at **[safedriving@tso.co.uk](mailto:safedriving@tso.co.uk)**.

Thank you for your valued custom.
